Guide to the Cascadilla School publications, 1887-1932.
Cascadilla School publications, 1887-1932.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cascadilla School publications, 1887-1932.
1152
Cascadilla School (Ithaca, N.Y.)
.1 cubic ft.
Catalogues, a prospectus, a yearbook, and pictures.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Catalogues (1887, 1893-1894, 1896-1897, 1923-1924, 1924-1925, 1931-1932), prospectus and yearbook (ca. 1900), and pictures of the school (ca. 1900).
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cascadilla School was a boarding school for boys in Ithaca, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Catalogues (1887, 1893-1894, 1896-1897, 1923-1924, 1924-1925, 1931-1932), prospectus and yearbook (ca. 1900), and pictures of the school (ca. 1900).
Accession folder contains a "Catalogue of Students of the Cascadilla School, 1876-94."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cascadilla School (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Boarding schools--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Education--New York (State)--Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cascadilla School Catalogue, 1893-1894 (Box 1)
- Cascadilla School Catalogue (+ duplicate), 1883 (Box 1)
- Cascadilla School items, ca. 1900
  - Prospectus and viewbook, containing endorsements of Jacob Gould Schurman, Charles Kendall Adams, R.H. Thurston, E.A. Fuertes and photographs and descriptions of the school and its facilities (Box 1)
  - Special announcement concerning innovations: a separate home for younger boys and a recreation building (Box 1)
  - Leaflet of department of physical culture (Box 1)
- Cascadilla School Catalogue, 1896-1897 (Box 1)
  Prospectus and viewbook, containing endorsements by Jacob Gould Schurman and Charles Kendall Adams, pictures of student rooms, buildings, etc.
- Pictures of Cascadilla School buildings and activities, apparently removed from a catalogue printed in the late '90s (10 pcs.) (Box 1)
  Wait Hall, West Front; main dining room; boys' room and principal's office; residence and Wait Hall, west front; the residence, East Front; new boat house; Wait Hall vestibule and '96 crew practicing on new rowing machines; '94 crew and C.U. from the Cascadilla School residence; new boat house (from Fall Creek) and the 1895 crew; east veranda of residence
- The Cascadilla School - 1 sheet announcement, 1887 (Box 1)
- Cascadilla School Catalogue, 1924-1925 (Box 1)